[Music]
every weekday i
shut down my classroom going through the
same routine of wiping tables and chairs
resetting the children's activities and
reflecting on the day
my life often feels quite ordinary i'm
tired at the end of my shifts and look
forward to going home
relaxing and settling into a good book
[Music]
on still autumn afternoons i like to
walk through the aspen groves and visit
with the cottonwoods
within a month they have burst into a
storm of color
that puts me in a nostalgic mood it's
time to appeal to my inner child and
sail some fairy boats skip stones and
imagine far-off lands full of whimsy
and wonder
[Music]
in the midst of all this beauty i
remember why i aspire to live
quietly working a job that serves my
community
and pursuing my hobbies without worrying
about success
as defined by someone else's standards
as children we are asked what we want to
be when we grow up
the accepted answer is often a
profession of some sort
in my case i wanted to be either a
veterinarian or a narwhal writer
we are not often asked if we will grow
up to be kind
or gentle or helpful will we be
givers or takers will we be our own best
friend
and will we be open to the possibility
that we are sometimes wrong in our way
of thinking
and that people and opportunities come
our way in order to challenge our minds
and strengthen our souls
[Music]
do
my life is full of routines and
inconsequential moments
but when magnified they become far more
meaningful
holding my student's hand the raindrops
on a spider's web
the smell of freshly grated beeswax
even something as mundane as bringing my
own bags to the grocery store
little experiences like these are what
make up most of my life
and consequently it makes sense to find
beauty and purpose in them
[Music]
for example the most exciting thing i
did this week was try to learn how to
make dipped candles
it was a lot more challenging than i
thought it would be and required
patience that i did not have at the time
but i really enjoyed it anyway and know
that my future attempts
will only improve
[Music]
i recently came across a passage in a
book that spoke of how our actions
define who we are
and after that our thoughts and words it
made me think about the proudest moments
in my own life
when i did not want to do something and
yet still did because i knew it was
right
i used to feel guilty about this because
in my heart i had felt selfish at the
time
and yet chose to have my actions tell a
different story
that i think is what actually mattered
[Music]
the real challenge in my own life is
applying those acts of kindness to
myself
i had a lot of work to do this evening
and did not want to take a moment to
slow down and recharge and communicate
to others that i needed some time alone
but i did and let my worries rest a
while as i engross myself in the story
and peaceful thoughts
i've not yet mastered the act of
kindness to oneself
but i am learning
[Music]
you